(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-02T12:31:04.002059",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Cerah sekali hari ini.
It's so bright today.
Langit yang sangat biru.
Such a very blue sky.
Langit biru, membara hati.
Blue sky, burning heart.
Putih awan, setulus cintaku pun bersemi.
White clouds, as sincere as my blossoming love.
Ini kurange teh aja nih, ya.
I'm just lacking some tea here, yeah.
Hah, bentar kita baca chat dulu ya, guys.
Huh, wait, let's read the chat first, guys.
Kita up dulu.
Let's scroll up first.
"Bo, intro, Bo, intro."
"Eh, saya bukan Kobo ya."
"Eh, I'm not Kobo, ya."
"Panggil aku..."
"Call me..."
"Cebo."
Ya, sama-sama bos sih.
Well, both are bosses, though.
Tapi di sini saya bukan Kobo ya, tapi, oke.
But here I'm not Kobo, ya, but, okay.
Eh, intro dulu ya, guys.
Uh, intro first, ya, guys.
Eh, Bo, Cebo, Cebo.
Cebo Kanenru, siap menghujani hatimu dengan petir cintaku.
Cebo Kanenru, ready to rain on your heart with the lightning of my love.
Ancis!
Oke, mari kita lihat live chat lagi.
Okay, let's check the live chat again.
"Kak, itu ada gitar di belakang, coba mainin dong."
"Kak, there's a guitar in the back, try playing it."
"Aku dan keluargaku sangat ingin mendengar Kak Cebo bernyanyi."
"Me and my family really want to hear Kak Cebo sing."
"Eh, iya, ada gitar ya?"
"Eh, yeah, there's a guitar, ya?"
There's guitar here, so so is there, tapi...
There's a guitar here, so so is there, but...
Gimana ya, aku nggak pandai nyanyi, guys.
How is it, I'm not good at singing, guys.
"Please Kak, suara Kakak ganteng banget, pasti bagus kalau nyanyi."
"Please Kak, your voice is so handsome, it must be good if you sing."
Eh, aduh iya ya, ya udahlah shoga nai ya.
Eh, oh well, shoganai ya.
Tapi satu lagu aja ya, oke, only one song, oke, ya.
But just one song, okay, only one song, okay, yeah.
Maaf ya, guys, kalau sedikit gimana gitu, soalnya aku emang nggak pandai nyanyi.
Sorry, guys, if it's a bit awkward, because I'm really not good at singing.
Ya udah, let's go.
Oh well, let's go.
星みたいに隠れて、合わないピント
Hiding like stars, the focus is off
天使は、もうこの部屋にはいない
The angel is no longer in this room
顔も知らない人と目が合う、今日この頃
I make eye contact with strangers these days
何かを指針にして、動き始める歯車
Using something as a guide, the gears begin to move
私の耳を穿つような音
A sound that pierces my ears
ないものねだりで夜が明ける頃
By the time the night breaks with things I don't have
誰かの寝言が街を歩く頃
By the time someone's sleep talk walks through the town
ああ、なんて傑作だ
Ah, what a masterpiece
このままじゃ生きられない
If it stays like this, I can't live
私、いい子でいられない
I can't be a good girl!
星みたいに隠れて、合わないピント
Hidden like a star, the focus doesn't match
天使は、もうこの部屋にはいない
The angel is no longer in this room.
顔も知らない人と目が合う、今日この頃
I meet eyes with strangers lately,
何かを指針にして、動き始める歯車
taking something as a guide, the gears begin to move.
流れ弾の数が増えていくから
Since the number of stray bullets keeps increasing,
たまにあるラッキーじゃ、間に合わない
the occasional luck isn't enough.
名前も知らない、一つ目が合う今日この頃
I meet eyes with strangers whose names I don't know,
何かを指針にして、狂い始める歯車
taking something as a guide, the gears begin to spin wildly.
夢見る時間に限りがあること
That there's a limit to the time for dreaming,
期待した分、裏切られていく矛盾
the disappointment matches my expectations.
私じゃなきゃいけない、理由はどこだ
Without me, where is the reason I have to be?
ああ、なんて失敗作
Ah, what a failure.
踊りを歩きたい誰もが私
I want to walk down the main street,
じゃなきゃ嫌だ
or else I won't have it any other way.
臆病も誤魔化しちゃ
Even cowardice starts to creep in,
一人きりなら泣きの優しさ Oh yeah I help
just self-centered kindness... (Help)
Please go away!
罵詈雑言 but 宇宙の上
Abuse on top of the universe,
一触即発ばっかじょう、もう夢を見たい
hair-trigger situations, I want to dream already.
Mimpi terasa jauh, ku terkurung
My dreams feel far away, I'm locked up,
Bagai mesin tak berdaya, hampa dan tak bernyawa
like a powerless machine, empty and lifeless,
Karna ku tak punya pilihan
because I have no other choice.
Help!! このままじゃ、楽しくない
Help!! If it stays like this, it's not fun.
Daddy, mummy 私、毛先も遊ばせたい
Daddy, mummy, I want to let my hair tips play too!
ほらね Help!! 面倒なんて、全部大正解
See? Help!! It's a hassle, so everything is a perfect answer.
あれもこれも好き放題、私は叶えるの
I can do whatever I want with this and that, I will make it happen.
Help!! このままじゃ生きられない
Help!! If it stays like this, I can't live.
Daddy, mummy 私、いい子じゃいられない
Daddy, mummy, I can't be a good child.
だから Help!! 今だけを見つめていたい
So, help!! I just want to stare at this moment.
そう、今だけ零さないように
Yes, so that I don't spill this moment.
Sekkaku...
Such a waste...
Keren banget gak sih? Sheesh!
Isn't that cool? Sheesh!
Suara... Kobo... eh cebo maksudnya? Lagu keren, suara keren ya nggak?
My voice... I mean Cebo? Cool song, cool voice, right?
Jadi... udah disemangatin sih, kencot suru demo ya disemangatin sama bang Natori jadi aku mau jadi lebih keren.
I was encouraged by Natori-sempai, so I want to be even cooler.
Uriaaa!
Kok mendung gini? Kalau hujan gini kan nggak jadi keren.
Why is it getting cloudy? If it rains like this, it won't be cool.
Nih timing hujannya nggak bisa di-delay ya. Em... Kasa. Pakai gitar apa nggak ya? Jangan ya. Ah, kata nggak.
The rain timing can't be delayed. Um... Should I use a guitar or not? Better not.
Ya udah, sekata nggak tanpa payung pun. Aku pasti bisa.
Oh well, without an umbrella either. I can definitely do it.
Mite! Kono renshama no pawaaa!
Look! This rain shaman's power!
Eh? Kobo? Kobo, kenapa aneh? Bangun, bangun, bangun! Hello? Help?
Huh? Kobo? What's wrong? Wake up, wake up, wake up! Hello? Help?
Poko poko... Come on! Bangun, bangun! Gugaga! Gugaga! No no no no no! Chotto matte!
Poko poko... Come on! Wake up, wake up! Gugaga! Gugaga! No! Wait a minute!
Gugaga! No! We can't do this again!
I'm here for your anniversary, not to raise you from a baby up again!
Gugaga! Hoho! Usu usu~ むにゅにゅ～
Gugaga! Hoho! Usu usu~ Munyunya~
What is you saying now? Usu usu~ むしゅしゅしゅ~
What are you saying now? Usu usu~ Usu usu~
A blue kid has been suspended by the sky, the sky angyyy!!!
Oh, why would the sky be angry about my sweet child?
She had treat the sky roughly!!
She had treated the sky roughly!!
I believe there's a misunderstanding here.
Please bring her back to normal, I beg you!
hoho~ in order to bring her back to normal, is to train her to be an idol!!!!!! Good luck
Okay Kobo, come on, let's just go inside first, okay? And then we'll talk about it.
Can you stand up and walk normally?
I know you can, go try, try!
You've done this before many years ago.
I dare you, go!
Okay, you know what? If you gambaru and do your best to walk on your own, then I will make your favorite food at home!
Okay, you know what? If you try your best to walk on your own, I'll make your favorite food at home!
Let's go home pokopokopon... Let's go home, okay? Here we are, back!
Attention! Attention! Attention, please!
Time for your first lesson, because apparently we're here with a lot of kids,
but I think I would like some introductions first, okay? So we have some order here! Let's try, okay? Let's begin with...
Are you... are you? Tell me your name.
I... Yopi! Yopi baby!
Your name is Yopi? Yopi, okay! Turn... Very good, baby! Okay, good.
I go next to you! Who are you?
Introduction... Um... Baby... Baby... Oh, okay, good job! Thank you!
Who are you, cutie patootie?
Okay, okay! Very good!
And now, because I seem to not be able to recognize my own child today, who are you?
Okay, I guess it was Kobo after all. Good job, everybody! Well done, you did so well!
Kobo, do you remember who I am?
Mama! Mama! Mama!
Mama, but also known as Takanashi Kiara from Hololive English Myth. And today, I seem to be the babysitter of this group!
But, but, but, chotto matte. Why are these babies here anyway? What's going on?
Hoho! Usu usu~
I thought I made only Kobo into a baby, but it seems that all the girls on this island have become babies!
Kiara, I asked you to babysit!
ここよ！ここよ！
Look over here! Look over here!
Did you understand?
わかった！わかった！オッケー！
Understood! Understood! Okay!
Doesn't matter. Everybody, I think we should play a game.
やったー！オッケー！
Yay! Okay!
No problem, I have an idea. We're gonna draw something over there. I'm gonna draw something, and you all will guess what it is.
わかった？わかった？And if you get it right, you'll get a big cake!
Understood? Understood? And if you get it right, you'll get a big cake!
やったー！オッケー！
Yay! Okay!
Are you ready? はい！オッケー、we will start with round one.
Are you ready? Yes! Okay, we will start with round one.
While I draw, you will behave, e-go-ni-shite-ne?
While I draw, you will behave, okay?
Okay, it's finished. Everybody, please take a look.
見て、見て。What is this thing?
Look, look. What is this thing?
Okay, I will ask you now.
これは何でしょう？
What could this be?
It's a potential answer. もしかしたらそうかもしれないけど。
It's a potential answer. It might just be...
What does Yopi-chan think that this is? カバ！カバ！コボ、カバ！カバ！
What does Yopi-chan think that this is? A hippo! Hippo! Kobo, hippo! Hippo!
I don't think so, but we will see. We will see.
What? What do you think that is over there? 王子！王子！
What? What do you think that is over there? A prince! A prince!
Is my drawing that bad? そんなに？そんなにひどい？そんなにひどい？あ、ぶた！ぶこぼ！
Is my drawing that bad? Is it really that bad? Is it really that bad? Oh, a pig! Pig-Kobo!
Not unchi right? What is this? Tell me.
Not poop right? What is this? Tell me.
いんご？いんご？いんご？りんご？りんご？
Ingo? Ingo? Ingo? Ringo? Ringo?
はい、YES!
Yes, YES!
オッケー、round two!
Okay, round two!
Start time! あ、しよう。オッケー、please behave, okay?
Start time! I'll show. Okay, please behave, okay?
鹿！鹿！
A deer! A deer!
待って、待って。ないよ！ないよ！ないよ！
Wait, wait. No way! No way! No way!
I finished, I finished! お、お、お、お。 I finished, okay?
I finished, I finished! Oh, oh, oh, oh. I finished, okay?
Look at this! じゃじゃーん！
Look at this! Tada!
Let's think, what could it be? Does it look nice? Does it look like an animal?
Yopi, what do you think that that is?
ドリアン！ドリアン！ドリアン！
Durian! Durian! Durian!
Maybe, maybe.
So also durian? ぐふふふ。 Maybe, maybe could be.
So also durian? Hehe. Maybe, maybe could be.
People, what is that over there?
バナナ！バナナ！
Banana! Banana!
You know banana is yellow. あー、オッケー、オッケー！
You know banana is yellow. Ah, okay, okay!
Please save me, what is this?
Ah!
Aaaaa!
Yeah? Yeah?
Nggak, aning!
No, aning!
Aaaaa!
Diam! Diam!
Quiet! Quiet!
Diam!
Quiet!
What is aning?
Diam!
Quiet!
Aning?
Aing?
Okay!
Aing, okay!
Aaaaa!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Hit more! Hit more!
Aaaaa!
Nyak! Nya!
What was that?
Okay.
Calm down. One more round.
Last round, okay?
Start!
Amo amo...
Aaaa... Ah...
Aaaaa!
Finish! Finish!
This. Look. Ta-da!
What is this?
It's not so difficult, right? You can, you know.
How about this time?
We ask Kobo first.
What do you think that is?
You know it.
Ogaka! Ogaka!
Ogaka? Ogaka!
Ogaka! Ogaka! Okay.
Probably... I will ask them too, okay?
What do you think that is?
Awww... wawa...
Ogawa! Wawa! Wawa!
Ama... Ama...
What do you think that is?
Tonnyato! Tonnyato!
Tonnyato?
What do you think?
Tomato! Tomato!
Tomato!
Boko Bo's correct?
Okaka! Okaka! Okaka!
Tornado! Tornado!
Be good! Be good!
Tornado!
Kids, how about we get along better together and nakayoshi shimashou by singing a song?
Kids, how about we get along better together and become good friends by singing a song?
Do you want to sing a song?
Yeah! Yeah!
Yutubu Kobo, Yutubu, it's okay, come back up.
Come back up. They will not bully you anymore, okay? We'll have fun now, banzai!
Come back up. They will not bully you anymore, okay? We'll have fun now, playtime!
Okay! Singing time!
Singing time! Yay!
チッチッチッチ モチモチモチモ チモシー きもち ウレシィ って マジ
Tick, tick, tick, mochi-mochi, timothy, feeling so happy, seriously!
チッチッチッチ モチモチモチモ チモシー って マジ タノシー きもち
Tick, tick, tick, mochi-mochi, timothy, having so much fun!
雨降って 地固まる… ケド 「幸運な場合」 って 条件がナイ?
Rain falling, ground hardening... But isn't "good luck" a required condition?
晴れ もっと いいことがある! それ強運の範囲って状況 the nice
Sunny days bring even better things! That's high-fortune territory, nice situation.
チッチッチッチ モチモチもし ももし ピンチがきて チモシーがいて
Tick, tick, tick, mochi-mochi, if a pinch comes and timothy is there,
チッチッチッチ もちろん だ まじ 待ってろって 任せて say! チモシー
Tick, tick, tick, of course, seriously, just wait, leave it to me, say! Timothy
四葉のクローバー 採れれば それは葉っぱ? yes, happy
Four-leaf clover, if you pick it, is that just a leaf? yes, happy
チモシー 頼もしいらしい あと やさしいって話し メルシー
Timothy seems reliable, and they say kind, merci
あっちこっち 立チマチ 変わる 天気予報は ふむふむ で もふもふ…
Everywhere, instantly changing weather forecast, hmm-hmm and fluffy...
フムフム でも スキップ インチき 立つも いかない だらけ
Hmm-hmm, but skipping, cheating, standing, not going anywhere, full of it
チッチッチッチ モチモチ モチモ ミチノ チモシー いかないだらけ
Tick, tick, tick, mochi-mochi, michino timothy, full of not going anywhere
チッチッチッチ モチモチモ ミチノ チモシー
Tick, tick, tick, mochi-mochi, michino timothy
きみのきもち、まみむめも
Kimi no kimochi, mami mume memo
雨のち晴れて、なんかちょっとファンシー
Ame nochi harete, nanka chotto fanshi
ちちちちちもちも、ちちちちもちいいきもち
Chichi chichi chimochimo, chichi chimochii kmochi
雨だけどづいてない、いつもくぎのらぎなさんなまいにち
Ame dakedo zuitenai, itsukute nogi na son na mainichi
あれだけどふりにみたい、しじくぜのらきたもんじゃない
Are dakedo furi ni mitai, shijukuze nora ki ta mon ja nai
ちちちちちもちも、びむびんちがききてるちもちいいがいて
Chichi chichi chimochimo, bimubinchi ga kiteru chimochii ga ite
ちちちちちもちべしょん、あげみってるてももっといてだけ、みんなどらもらなんださのもとたみじ
Chichi chimochibeshon, age mitteru temo motto ite dake, minna doramora nanda sa no moto tamzi
ちもちわかわほえらし、してもくらしいなかんじちもちゆん
Chimochi wa kowai hodo, shitemo kurashii na kanji chimochiyun
まじこっちまいにち、はれゆくよほわ
Maji kocchi mainichi, hare yuku yo ho wa
まじまじとほもおも、とにかくこにかしてあげましょ
Maji maji toh o mo o mo, tonika conica shite agemasho
ちちちちちもちも、みちのちもち
Chichi chichi chimochimo, michino chimochi
ちちちちちもちも、つみなきもち
Chichi chichi chimochimo, tsumi na kimochi
まみむめも、みんなのらぶきゃっち
Mami mume memo, minna no rabukacchi
たてあいごるだし
Tate ai goru dashi
きょみきょみきょみるったんか、くろいめのくもをまとみこえ
Kyomkyomkyom uru-tta n-ka, kuroi me no kumo o matomikoe
かわうさぎだけど、ひと肌ぬいじゃいましょう、ついておいでよ
Kawa usagi dakedo, hitohada nui jaimasho, tsuite oide yo
ちちちちちもちも、ちちちちもちいいきもち
Chichi chichi chimochimo, chichi chimochii kimochi
きみのきもち、まみむめも
Kimi no kimochi, mami mume memo
雨のち晴れて、なんかちょっとファンシー
Ame nochi harete, nanka chotto fanshi
ちちちちちもちも、みちのちもち
Chichi chichi chimochimo, michino chimochi
ちちちちちもちも、つみなきもち
Chichi chichi chimochimo, tsumi na kimochi
まみむめも、みんなのらぶきゃっち
Mami mume memo, minna no rabukacchi
たてぼくとはちもし
Tate-bo-kuto wa chimoshi
Yeah!
Good job, everybody! We can eat some cake! Let's go!
Stinky! Eco-chan! Stinky! Eco-chan! Kobo is taking a shower!
Ha... Better.
Washa washa... Washa washa washa...
Washa washa with...
Mandi Biar Wangi ☆ Washa Washa!
Habis bermain, keringat bercucuran
Rambut jadi lepek juga berminyak
Tapi ku lelah, ku ingin tidur saja
Memangnya cuci muka tidak cukup kah?
Bau badan tak tertahankan, mami papi ku kewalahan
Katanya mereka ku harus pergi mandi secepatnya
Washa washa wah, ku cuci rambut ku
Washa washa wah, ku gosok badan ku
Habis bermain, keringat bercucuran
After playing, sweat is dripping
Rambut jadi lepek, juga berminyak
Hair is limp and greasy too
Tapi ku lelah, ku ingin tidur saja
But I'm tired, I just want to sleep
Memangnya cuci muka tidak cukup, kah?
Is washing my face not enough?
Bau badan tak tertahankan
Body odor is unbearable
Mami, Papi ku kewalahan
Mami, Papi are overwhelmed
Katanya mereka, 'ku harus pergi mandi secepatnya'
They say, "You must go take a bath as soon as possible"
Washa washa wah, ku cuci rambut ku
Washa washa wah, I wash my hair
Washa washa wah, ku gosok badan ku
Washa washa wah, I scrub my body
Shikishi, kishi, ku sikat gigi
Shikishi, kishi, I brush my teeth
Sekarang sudah wangi
Now it's fragrant
Shoko shoko sho, keringkan rambut ku
Shoko shoko sho, I dry my hair
Shoko shoko sho, keringkan badan ku
Shoko shoko sho, I dry my body
Pakai baju untuk tidur, bersiap 'tuk ke kasur
Put on pajamas, get ready for bed
Selamat malam mami, papi
Good night Mami, Papi
Selamat pagi, tapi masih dikasur
Good morning, but still in bed
Tangan dan kakiku malas bergerak
My hands and feet are too lazy to move
Ku masih ngantuk, ku ingin tidur saja
I'm still sleepy, I just want to sleep
Memangnya nggak bisa bentar lagi, kah?
Can't it be just a little longer?
Perut sakit, ku kelaparan
Stomach hurts, I'm hungry
Mami, Papi ku kewalahan
Mami, Papi are overwhelmed
Katanya mereka, 'ku harus pergi mandi sebelum makan'
They say, "You must go take a bath before eating"
Washa washa wah, ku cuci rambut ku
Washa washa wah, I wash my hair
Washa washa wah, ku gosok badan ku
Washa washa wah, I scrub my body
Shikishi, kishi, ku sikat gigi
Shikishi, kishi, I brush my teeth
Sekarang sudah wangi
Now it's fragrant
Shoko shoko sho, keringkan rambut ku
Shoko shoko sho, I dry my hair
Shoko shoko sho, keringkan badan ku
Shoko shoko sho, I dry my body
Pakai seragam yang lengkap, bersiap 'tuk sekolah
Put on a complete uniform, get ready for school
Sampai jumpa mami, papi
See you later Mami, Papi
Mimpi indah menjadi nyata, untuk anak yang patuh aturan
Dreams, beautiful dreams become reality, for a child who follows the rules
Kelap-kelip bintang di langit, semua hal bisa kulakukan jika sudah mandi
Twinkle twinkle stars in the sky, everything I can do if I have bathed
Sampai jumpa mami, papi
See you later Mami, Papi
Mimpi indah menjadi nyata, untuk anak yang patuh aturan
Dreams, beautiful dreams become reality, for a child who follows the rules
Kelap-kelip bintang di langit, semua hal bisa kulakukan jika sudah mandi
Twinkle twinkle stars in the sky, everything I can do if I have bathed
Semua hal bisa kulakukan jika sudah mandi
Everything I can do if I have bathed
Jika aku rajin mandi, aku bisa menjadi putri di sesudahnya
If I bathe diligently, I can become a princess afterwards
Washa washa wah, ku cuci rambutku
Washa washa wah, I wash my hair
Washa washa wah, ku gosok badanku
Washa washa wah, I scrub my body
Shikishi, kishi, ku sikat gigi
Shikishi, kishi, I brush my teeth
Sekarang sudah wangi
Now it's fragrant
Washa washa wah, ku cuci rambutku
Washa washa wah, I wash my hair
Washa washa wah, ku gosok badanku
Washa washa wah, I scrub my body
Shikishi, kishi, ku sikat gigi
Shikishi, kishi, I brush my teeth
Cintai dirimu
Love yourself
Gugu gaga
Hey Kobo! I've been waiting for you here. Congrats on your third anniversary!
Gugu gaga!
Huh? Wait, why gugu gaga?
Ba-ba-ba-ba. Ba-ba-ba-ba.
Oh! I get it, you've been cursed!
Well, I'm actually familiar with curses, okay? So, what's up?
Ba-ba-ba-ba, ba-ba-ba-ba...
Okay, okay. I see. You're in training so that you can be an idol, so that you can talk normally.
Not all, don't, okay. So you can still dance and like sing just fine, but no talking.
Oh, okay. Well, maybe you need to perform with Dada.
Oh, okay, okay. Say... Dada.
Okay, all right, all right. You know what, let's just let's take it slow, okay? Let's take it slow!
マル・マル・モリ・モリ みんな食べるよ
Maru Maru Mori Mori, everyone eat it all!
ツル・ツル・テカ・テカ 明日も晴れるかな
Tsuru Tsuru Taka Taka, will it be sunny tomorrow too?
ダバデュア ダバジャバ 忘れ物すんなよ
Dabadua Dabajaba, don't forget anything!
ダバデュア ダバジャバ デュア
Dabadua Dabajaba Dua
大きくなったら お空に声が届くかな
When I grow up, will my voice reach the sky?
いつまでも 一緒だよ！
We'll be together forever!
いつまででも いっしょだよ
マル・マル・モリ・モリ みんな食べるよ
Maru Maru Mori Mori, everyone eat it all!
ツル・ツル・テカ・テカ 明日も晴れるかな
Tsuru Tsuru Taka Taka, will it be sunny tomorrow too?
悲しくて泣いていた 一人歩く帰り道
I was sad and crying, walking home alone.
こんな時ホンワカな みんなに会いたいな
At times like this, I want to see everyone.
マル・マル・モリ・モリ おまじないだよ
Maru Maru Mori Mori, it's a magic spell!
ツル・ツル・テカ・テカ ニッコリ笑顔
Tsuru Tsuru Taka Taka, a smiling face.
いち に の さん し で ゴマ塩さん
With 1, 2, 3, 4, it's Mr. Sesame-Salt.
たくさんだと おいしいね
It's delicious if there's a lot!
マル・マル・モリ・モリ プカ・プカ・オフロ
Maru Maru Mori Mori, puka puka in the bath.
ツル・ツル・ピカ・ピカ ゴシ・ゴシ・ブラシ
Tsuru Tsuru Pika Pika, goshi goshi with a brush.
皆さんグッドナイ また明日
Goodnight everyone, see you tomorrow.
朝ごはんは なんでしょう？
What's for breakfast?
ダバデュア ダバジャバ お腹だして寝るなよ
Dabadua Dabajaba, don't sleep with your belly exposed!
マル・マル・モリ・モリ プカ・プカ・オフロ
Maru Maru Mori Mori, puka puka in the bath.
ツル・ツル・ピカ・ピカ ゴシ・ゴシ・ブラシ
Tsuru Tsuru Pika Pika, goshi goshi with a brush.
皆さんグッドナイ また明日
Goodnight everyone, see you tomorrow.
朝ごはんは なんでしょう？
What's for breakfast?
いつもいつも ありがとう！
Always, always thank you!
ダバデュア ダバジャバ デュビデュバ
Dabadua Dabajaba Dubiduba
大人になっても 虹色の夢を描こうね
Even when we grow up, let's draw rainbow dreams!
指切りして テレリンコ
Let's make a pinky promise.
お星さま キレイだね 手をつないで願いごと
The stars are beautiful, holding hands and making a wish.
たとえ遠くにいても 心はひとつだよ
Even if we are far apart, our hearts are one.
マル・マル・モリ・モリ シアワセ元気
Maru Maru Mori Mori, happy and energetic.
テク・テク・トコ・トコ 前に進むよ
Teku Teku Toko Toko, moving forward.
いち に の さん し で ホームラン
A homerun on 1, 2, 3, 4!
愛がいっぱい ランドセル
A school bag full of love.
マル・マル・モリ・モリ 大きくなるよ
Maru Maru Mori Mori, I'll grow big!
ドキ・ドキ・ワク・ワク ドアを開けるよ
Doki Doki Waku Waku, opening the door.
皆さんしっかり また明日
Goodnight everyone, see you tomorrow.
もっとステキな日になる
It'll be an even better day!
大好きだよ！！！
I love you!
マル・マル・モリ・モリ さあ 歌いましょう！
Maru Maru Mori Mori, let's sing together!
ツル・ツル・テカ・テカ ニッコリ笑顔
Tsuru Tsuru Taka Taka, a smiling face.
いち に の さん し で ゴマ塩さん
With 1, 2, 3, 4, it's Mr. Sesame-Salt.
たくさんだと おいしいね
It's delicious if there's a lot!
マル・マル・モリ・モリ プカ・プカ・オフロ
Maru Maru Mori Mori, puka puka in the bath.
ツル・ツル・ピカ・ピカ ゴシ・ゴシ・ブラシ
Tsuru Tsuru Pika Pika, goshi goshi with a brush.
皆さんグッドナイ また明日
Goodnight everyone, see you tomorrow.
朝ごはんは なんでしょう？
What's for breakfast?
いつもいつも ありがとう！
Always, always thank you!
ダバデュア ダバジャバ デュビデュバ
Dabadua Dabajaba Dubiduba
ダバデュア ダバジャバ デュア
Dabadua Dabajaba Dua
よく出来ました！
Good job!
マル・マル・モリ・モリ みんな食べるよ
Maru Maru Mori Mori, everyone eat it all!
ツル・ツル・テカ・テカ 明日も晴れるかな
Tsuru Tsuru Taka Taka, will it be sunny tomorrow too?
ダバデュア ダバジャバ 忘れ物すんなよ
Dabadua Dabajaba, don't forget anything!
ダバデュア ダバジャバ デュア
Dabadua Dabajaba Dua
大きくなったら お空に声が届くかな
When I grow up, will my voice reach the sky?
いつまでも 一緒だよ！
We'll be together forever!
マル・マル・モリ・モリ みんな食べるよ
Maru Maru Mori Mori, everyone eat it all!
ツル・ツル・テカ・テカ 明日も晴れるかな
Tsuru Tsuru Taka Taka, will it be sunny tomorrow too?
いつもいつも ありがとう！
Always, always thank you!
ダバデュア ダバジャバ デュビデュバ
Dabadua Dabajaba Dubiduba
ダバデュア ダバジャバ デュア
Dabadua Dabajaba Dua
よくできました！
Good job!
So, so, so how was that? How is it now?
Still baby, huh? This is weird. You know, the curse should be lifted 'cause you did really, really...
Well, you're very like
アイドルみたい 可愛い 可愛いコボ、right?
You're like an idol! So cute, cute Kobo, right?
カリオペには少し仕事があるけど
Calliope's got a little bit of work to do though.
And what is wrong? I need to talk to that curse.
I will visit, I will visit whoever did this to you now, and I will boko-boko their ass!
I will visit whoever did this to you right now, and I'll beat their ass to a pulp!
So keep you laughing while I'm gonna get out of here
So keep laughing while I get the hell out of here!
My work here is done.
頑張れ 頑張れ バイバイ
Do your best, do your best! Bye-bye!
ギュッ！ギュッ！ ギュッギュッギュッ！
Gyu! Gyu! Gyu-gyu-gyu!
サンサンと おひさま笑顔 日曜日 おでかけしましょう
Bright and sunny, with a smiling sun on Sunday, let's go out!
はぐれないように しっかり 仲良くね 手をつないで
Hold hands tightly so we don't get separated.
ずっとずっとずっと一緒にいようね
Let's stay together forever and ever!
明日もあさっても 大人になっても 大好きだよ
Tomorrow, the day after, even when we grow up, I love you so much!
夢いっぱい ギュッ！ギュッ！ギュッ！
Full of dreams, gyu! gyu! gyu!
みんなでおにぎりを もぐもぐ ハッピーグッデイ
Munching on onigiri together, happy good day!
幸せを ギュッ！ギュッ！ギュッ！
Hugging happiness, gyu! gyu! gyu!
愛情たっぷりでおまんぷくぷくぷく
Stuffed full with plenty of love, pupu-puku-puku!
ニコニコほらね ココロが踊る
Smile and look, our hearts are dancing!
ステキな日曜日 ギュッギュッギュッのギュッ！
A wonderful Sunday, gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu!
ギュッ！ギュッ！ ギュッギュッギュッ！
Gyu! Gyu! Gyu-gyu-gyu!
ザアザアと 雨が降る日曜日 でも平気だよ
Pouring down, raining on Sunday, but it's totally fine!
傘さして 長靴はいて 出かけよう おしゃれをして
Put up an umbrella, wear boots, and head out in style!
ちょっとちょっとちょっと淋しい時でも
Even when you're feeling a little bit lonely,
水たまり跳ねて 君と遊んだら 忘れちゃうよ
splashing in puddles and playing with you makes it all fade away!
ハートいっぱい ギュッ！ギュッ！ギュッ！
Full of heart, gyu! gyu! gyu!
明日もまた会おうね 約束 ハッピーグッデイ
Let's promise to meet again tomorrow, happy good day!
想い出を ギュッ！ギュッ！ギュッ！
Hugging memories, gyu! gyu! gyu!
ココロのポケットに ウキウキしまおうね
Let's tuck our excitement safely into our heart's pocket!
雨が止んだら 虹が見えたよ
When the rain stopped, a rainbow appeared!
ステキな日曜日 ギュッギュッギュッのギュッ！
A wonderful Sunday, gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu!
ギュッ！ギュッ！ ギュッギュッギュッ！
Gyu! Gyu! Gyu-gyu-gyu!
おんなじ気持ち ひとつ増えたら
When we share the exact same feeling,
笑顔もひとつ増えるから
another smile is added to our faces too!
つかまえようよ たくさん集めよう 宝物
Let's catch them, let's gather up lots of treasures!
ねっ！
Right?
夢いっぱい ギュッ！ギュッ！ギュッ！
Full of dreams, gyu! gyu! gyu!
みんなでおにぎりを もぐもぐ ハッピーグッデイ
Munching on onigiri together, happy good day!
ねっ！
Right?
夢いっぱい ギュッ！ギュッ！ギュッ！
Full of dreams, gyu! gyu! gyu!
みんなでおにぎりを もぐもぐ ハッピーグッデイ
Munching on onigiri together, happy good day!
幸せを ギュッ！ギュッ！ギュッ！
Hugging happiness, gyu! gyu! gyu!
愛情たっぷりでおまんぷくぷくぷくぷく
Stuffed full with plenty of love, pupu-puku-puku-puku!
ニコニコほらね ココロが踊る
Smile and look, our hearts are dancing!
ステキな日曜日 ギュッギュッギュッのギュッ！
A wonderful Sunday, gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu!
ギュッ！ギュッ！ ギュッギュッギュッ！
Gyu! Gyu! Gyu-gyu-gyu!
はずむココロ！飛ぶようなテンション！
Heart skipping! Tension like flying!
さぁ connect しよう！
Let's connect now!
アレ！今こう思って、言って、あぁそうじゃなくって…
Huh? Thinking like this now, saying it, ah, that's not it...
伝わらないや、なんだっけ？どうするんだっけ…
Can't get it across, why was it? What was I going to do...
しっちゃかめっちゃか thinking
Messy, messy thinking
ぐるぐる now loading…
Spinning, now loading...
[ctrl] + [z] きかないし
[Ctrl] + [Z] doesn't work,
複雑カスタマイズ
Complex customization.
足りない？なにかインストールとかできたらなぁ
Not enough? If only I could install something like that
なんて不完全で
How incomplete
なんて不確実で
How uncertain
説明書なんかないよね まずは始めてみようかな…
There's no instruction manual, is there? Shall we start by trying it out first...?
違う姿 違うカタチ なのにどうして
Different appearance, different shape, even so, why is it?
おなじキモチ！
The same feeling!
繋がってる実感
The feeling of being connected
分け合うぬくもりありがとう
Thank you for the warmth we share
思いきり伝えたいんだ
I want to convey it with all my might
カラフル！笑顔！心地いいな♪
Colorful! Smile! It feels good ♪
繋がってくみんなと ここがわたしの好きな場所
Connecting with everyone, this is my favorite place.
はずむココロ！飛ぶようなテンション！
Heart skipping! Tension like flying!
いま connect しよう！
Let's connect now!
きっと頑張ってみたって 変われないって
Surely, even if I try my best, thinking I can't change
トライしてみる手前 断念して
Before I try, giving up
部屋でぼっち crying ネガティブばかり my mind
Crying alone in the room, negative only, my mind
想ったようにいかなくて ポッキリ折れた
It didn't go as I thought, snap, it broke
ココロもう一度 踊らせていきたいんだ
I want to make my heart dance once again
いいよ不完全で もう隠さないんだ
It's okay to be incomplete, I won't hide it anymore
理想へ届かなくても 一歩踏み出してみようかな…
Even if I can't reach my ideal, shall I try taking a step forward...?
違う色と 違う夢で 進むミライ
With a different color and a different dream, the future I advance to
きっとステキ！
Must be wonderful!
見えないけど感じる あたたかい優しさありがとう
I can't see it, but I can feel the warm kindness, thank you
思いきり歌いたいんだ ハピフル！笑顔！届けたいな♪
I want to sing with all my might! Happy full! Smile! I want to deliver it ♪
出逢っていくオリジナリティ みんなとの大切な場所
Originality that I meet, a precious place with everyone
ひとりでカンペキじゃなくていいんだ
It doesn't have to be perfect alone
みんなと一緒に going
Going together with everyone,
わたしにできること 見つけていくから ah
I will find out what I can do, ah
違う姿 違うカタチ なのにホントだ
Different appearance, different shape, even so, it's true,
おなじキモチ！
The same feeling!
繋がってる実感 分け合うぬくもりありがとう
The feeling of being connected, thank you for the warmth we share
思いきり伝えたいんだ カラフル！笑顔！心地いいな♪
I want to convey it with all my might! Colorful! Smile! It feels good ♪
繋がってくみんなと ここがわたしの好きな場所
Connecting with everyone, this is my favorite place.
ひとりじゃカンペキじゃなくていいんだ
It doesn't have to be perfect alone
みんなと一緒にならいっぱい力にできること
Going together with everyone, I can turn it into so much power
見つけていくから
I'll keep finding it
違う姿 違うカタチ なのに本当だ おなじキモチ！
Different appearance, different shape, even so, it's true, the same feeling!
繋がってる実感 分け合うぬくもりありがとう
The feeling of being connected, thank you for the warmth we share
思いきり伝えたいんだ カラフル！笑顔！心地いいな♪
I want to convey it with all my might! Colorful! Smile! It feels good ♪
繋がってくみんなと ここがわたしの好きな場所
Connecting with everyone, this is my favorite place.
はずむココロ！飛ぶようなテンション！
Heart skipping! Tension like flying!
さぁ connect しよう！
Let's connect now!
いたい！いた！た、た、た、え？
Ouch! Ouch, ou-ou-ouch! Huh?
I can speak? Wow! And my dress chi...
I can speak? Wow! And my dress ch...
おめでとう！これできた力を取り戻したね！
Congrats, you have now gotten back your power!
えーーー！わぁ！ I've gotten back my power now! And my my dress my my my ほぐ is changin'
Heh?! Woah! I've gotten back my power now! And my dress, my clothes are changing!
Why do I have マイクと？あ、でも anyway thank you!
Why do I have a mic too? Ah, but anyway, thank you!
Thank you Cielos, now I can talk normally! やったー！
Thank you Cielos, now I can talk normally! Yay!
You're such a good friend! でも、なんで？このボボルスから逃げたニャ？
You're such a good friend! But why did you run away from Boborus?
What is this mic for? Huh?
I hope you have a great day, Happy 3rd Anniversary!
Sekarang waktunya...
Now, it's time...
Cilus!
Apa tuh Cilus? Ya, jadi Cilus ini maksudnya...
What's Cilus? Well, what Cilus means is...
Merch kali ini adalah... Cilus! Boneka Cilus! Cilus plushie, yoroshiku! Kawaii desho?
This time's merch is... Cilus! Cilus plushie! Cilus plushie, please check it out! Cute, right?
Eh, yasui! Hahaha! Eh, ya ya ya, kore yasui! Zettai katte ne! Kawaii dakara ne!
Eh, cheap! Hahaha! Eh, yeah yeah yeah, this is cheap! You definitely have to buy it! Because it's cute, you know!
Jadi kalian harus punya Cilus sebagai teman tidur kalian, teman mandi kalian...
So you guys must have Cilus as your sleeping buddy, bathing buddy...
...teman motoran kalian, bisa menjadi teman kalian yang enggak punya teman.
...riding buddy, and someone to be a friend for those who don't have friends.
Anyways, tolong dibeli karena bisa habis, iya. Jadi jangan sampe kehabisan, karena nggak apa-apa harus aja beli pokoknya.
Anyways, please buy it because it can run out, yeah. So don't run out, because it's fine, you just have to buy it anyway.
Oke! Kalau gitu...
Okay! If that's the case...
Udah nih, kita jual Cilus udah, promo Cilus udah nih jual plushie Cilus.
That's it, we're done selling Cilus, done promoting Cilus, selling Cilus plushie.
Oke, selanjutnya apa? Udah selesai kita, kita udah di penghujung acara, guys.
Okay, what's next? We're done, we're at the end of the event, guys.
Ya udah deh, kalau gitu, see you next time ya! Kobo mau ngucapin makasih udah ngikutin perjalanan Kobo, perjalanan gogogaga ini. Miku-chan tte itte arigatou! Mitekurete arigatou! Thank you for accompanying me in this baby gogogaga journey.
Alright then, if so, see you next time! Kobo wants to say thank you for following Kobo's journey, this gogogaga journey. Thank you for watching! Thank you for accompanying me in this baby gogogaga journey.
Ja, otsukaresu! See you next time! Bye-bye!
Well then, good job! See you next time! Bye-bye!
Eh? Halo?
Eh? Hello?
Ini di mana ya? Arsy? Arsy Widianto?
Where is this? Arsy? Arsy Widianto?
Iya, halo. Kita udah kenal—
Yeah, hello. We already know—
Enggak Kobo, pawang hujan, 8 tahun. Sudah punya pengalaman 3 tahun. Ini pengalaman ketiga tahun, penggemar ringan Arsy Widianto!
No Kobo, rain shaman, 8 years old. Already has 3 years of experience. This is the 3rd year of experience, lightweight fan Arsy Widianto!
Selamat, happy third anniversary ya, Kobo.
Congratulations, happy third anniversary, Kobo.
Cilus plushie! Yang sempat melayang...
Cilus plushie! Which was floating...
Eh tapi betul bukan ya? Bukannya kayak Arsy sibuk ya, orangnya kok bisa tiba-tiba di sini?
Eh but is that right? Isn't Arsy busy, how could he suddenly be here?
Enggak tahu, tadi aja tiba-tiba kayak aku ditarik di bawah terbang sama awan. Gitu aja. Hah? Sama awan?
I don't know, just now suddenly it was like I was pulled flying under by a cloud. Just like that. Huh? By a cloud?
Iya. Eh. Oh. Betewe. Eh, ya?
Yeah. Eh. Oh. By the way. Eh, yeah?
Aku tuh sebenarnya udah kenal kamu, Bo. Hah? Iya. Arsy Widianto-kun.
I actually already know you, Bo. Huh? Yeah. Arsy Widianto-kun.
Aku cuma pura-pura lupa aja. Jangan-jangan kamu beneran lupa ya, Bo?
I was just pretending to forget. Don't tell me you actually forgot, Bo?
Ah, aku... banyak yang hal terjadi hari ini. Walau aku sedikit sakit...
Ah, I... a lot of things happened today. Even though I'm a little sick...
It's okay, Kobo, nggak apa-apa.
It's okay, Kobo, it's fine.
Tapi kenapa ya, perasaan ini familiar? Seakan kita sudah saling kenal satu sama lain sebelumnya.
But why does this feeling feel familiar? As if we've already known each other before.
Seberat itu trauma kamu, Bo?
Is your trauma that heavy, Bo?
Maaf Arsy...
Sorry Arsy...
Sebenarnya aku ingin dekatmu
Actually, I want to be close to you
Namun kusadari ku tak bisa, tak boleh ku di sini
But I realize I can't, I shouldn't be here
Bahaya ku makin cinta
It's dangerous, I'm falling more in love
Ku tak ingin jauh
I don't want to be far
Tak ingin berpisah
Don't want to part ways
Mengapa semua selalu indah saat denganmu?
Why is everything always beautiful when I'm with you?
Sayang untuk diakhiri
It's a pity to end it
Andai engkau bisa mengerti betapa beratnya aku
If only you could understand how heavy it is for me
Harus aku tetap tersenyum padahal hatiku terluka
I must keep smiling even though my heart is hurt
Adakah arti cinta ini bila ku tak jadi denganmu?
Is there any meaning to this love if I don't end up with you?
Jika memang ku harus pergi
If indeed I have to leave
Sebenarnya aku ingin dekatmu
Actually I want to be near you
Namun kusadari, ku tak bisa
But I realize I can't
Tak boleh ku di sini
I'm not allowed to be here
Bahaya, ku makin cinta
It's dangerous, I'm falling in love even more
Bukankah semesta
Isn't it the universe
yang pertemukan kita?
that brought us together?
Haruskah ku sampaikan pada bintang?
Should I convey it to the stars?
Mengapa bukan kamu
Why isn't it you
yang memiliki aku?
who possesses me?
Andai engkau bisa mengerti
If only you could understand
betapa beratnya aku
how heavy it is for me
Harus aku tetap tersenyum
I have to keep smiling
padahal hatiku terluka
even though my heart is hurt
Adakah arti cinta ini
Is there meaning to this love
bila ku tak jadi denganmu?
if I don't end up with you?
Jika memang ku harus pergi
If I really have to go
yakinlah, hatiku kamu
believe me, my heart is yours
Mengapa cinta pertemukan bila akhirnya dipisahkan?
Why did love bring us together if in the end we are separated?
Dan mengapa ku jatuh cinta pada cinta yang tak jatuh padaku?
And why did I fall in love with a love that doesn't fall for me?
Harus aku tetap tersenyum padahal hatiku terluka
I have to keep smiling even though my heart is hurt
Adakah arti cinta ini bila ku tak jadi denganmu?
Is there meaning to this love if I don't end up with you?
Jika memang ku harus pergi yakinlah, hatiku kamu
If I really have to go, believe me, my heart is yours
Harus aku tetap tersenyum
I have to keep smiling
padahal hatiku terluka
even though my heart is hurt
Adakah arti cinta ini
Is there meaning to this love
bila ku tak jadi denganmu?
if I don't end up with you?
Jika memang ku harus pergi
If I really have to go
yakinlah, hatiku kamu
believe me, my heart is yours
Harus aku tetap tersenyum
I have to keep smiling
padahal hatiku terluka
even though my heart is hurt
Adakah arti cinta ini
Is there meaning to this love
bila ku tak jadi denganmu?
if I don't end up with you?
Jika memang ku harus pergi
If I really have to go
yakinlah, hatiku kamu
believe me, my heart is yours
Yakinlah cinta
Believe in love
untukmu...
for you...
Gitu ya, guys. Kita jadi pemeran film.
Like that, guys. We became movie characters.
Bisa, bisa ini kayaknya nih, cocok nih.
We could, this seems like it, it fits.
Nih, super mega bintang nih kayaknya kalau main film nih kayaknya nih.
This looks like a super mega star if we star in a movie.
Ayo, kapan nih collab? Next collab kita.
Come on, when's the collab? Our next collab.
Ayo dong, ayo dong.
Let's go, let's go.
Ah, gas.
Ah, let's go.
Atau yang satunya juga, eh apaan tuh yang satunya?
Or the other one too, eh what is that other one?
Apasih, spoiler ini guys.
What is it, this is a spoiler guys.
Enggak, enggak, enggak.
No, no, no.
Eh gimana, gimana? Gimana, senang enggak? Makasih ya udah mau diundang.
Eh how is it, how is it? How is it, happy? Thanks for wanting to be invited.
Aku yang harusnya berterima kasih. Aku happy banget. Ini salah satu pengalaman yang berharga banget, terindah banget buat aku, especially ada kamu di sini, menamani aku.
I'm the one who should thank you. I'm so happy. This is one of the most precious experiences, the most beautiful for me, especially having you here, accompanying me.
Ya aku sih yang nemenin kamu sebenarnya. Aku senang banget bisa menemani. Ini pengalaman yang best banget. Jadi terima kasih banyak.
Well, I'm the one accompanying you actually. I'm so happy to accompany you. This is the best experience. So thank you very much.
Makasih banget.
Thank you very much.
Ya makasih kembali.
Yeah, thanks to you too.
Gitu ya guys, tapi sayangnya cuma bentar.
Like that guys, but sadly it's only for a short while.
Aku sebenarnya masih pengin lebih lama sih sama kamu.
I actually still want to be with you longer.
Nih, emang Arsy Widianto emang sepintar ini ya kalau ngomong ya, kalau berkata-kata.
This, is Arsy Widianto really this smart at talking, at choosing words?
Emang, emang itu pintar. Aku mah, ini mah dari hati aja, apa adanya.
Yeah, that's smart. As for me, this is just from the heart, just as it is.
Eh tapi, urusan lagu-lagunya tuh.
Eh but, regarding the songs.
Aku tuh enggak bisa tahu. Aku tuh pernah nulis lagu romantis gitu, cuman tuh enggak bisa. Aku tuh harus ngebayangan nya tuh fake gitu loh, membayangkan keadaan yang fake gitu.
I couldn't know. I once wrote a romantic song like that, but I couldn't. I had to imagine it being fake, imagining a fake situation.
Menurut aku, bisa. Semua orang tuh bisa. Bicara cinta, semua orang pasti memiliki jalan cintanya sendiri.
In my opinion, you can. Everyone can. Talking about love, everyone surely has their own path of love.
Kamu juga pasti punya dengan apapun, dengan hal-hal indah. Jadi, kamu akan menemukan sendiri jalannya dan...
You surely have it too with whatever, with beautiful things. So, you will find the path yourself and...
Pasti akan ada sih pertanda-tanda Qomun.
There's definitely gonna be signs of Qomun.
Wow, apakah... Apakah Araya-tadashi akan tergantikan? Kan? Yamakun?
Wow, will... will Araya-tadashi be replaced? Right? Yamakun?
Eh ya.
Uh, yeah.
Ya anyways, makasih advice-nya. Banyak sekali pelajaran yang bisa diambil dari stream ini. Terima kasih ya, Bang Arsy Widianto kun.
Yeah anyways, thanks for the advice. So many lessons to be learned from this stream. Thank you, Bang Arsy Widianto-kun.
Aku juga berterima kasih banget. Aku happy banget.
I'm also very grateful. I'm so happy.
Jadi aku lanjut ya.
So I'll continue.
Ih, enggak, enggak ilfil kan nih? Diundang sama VTuber ya?
Hey, you're not turned off, right? Getting invited by a VTuber?
Enggaklah.
No way.
Eh, enggak ya? Eh, kalau buat kamu mah apa sih yang enggak?
Oh, really? Well, for you, is there anything that isn't?
Udahlah, tenang aja.
Alright, just relax.
Ayo, ayo kita... Kita kayak... Coba-coba di-pet-pet, bisa enggak kita kecilnya?
Come on, let's... We're like... Try patting, can we make it smaller?
Iya iya iya... Kok kayak pendek banget sih aku? Aku enggak sempendek ini deh, harusnya. Hah? Hah? Hah? Hah?
Yeah yeah yeah... Why am I so short? I shouldn't be this short, surely. Huh? Huh? Huh? Huh?
Parah banget. Yuk, kita... Kita... Fist bump, fist bump, fist bump.
That's awful. Come on, let's... Fist bump, fist bump, fist bump.
Fist bump.
Fist bump. Uh-huh. Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
High five! High five! Yeah! Yay!
Ya udah deh. Oke, baiklah, terima kasih banyak sekali lagi. Kobo, makasih banget.
Alright then. Okay, well, thank you so much once again. Kobo, thank you so much.
Jangan ke mana-mana, ikut... Ini enggak? Makan-makan dulu kita.
Don't go anywhere, join... Wait, no? Let's eat first.
Mau ke mana? Mau makan apa? Ayo, mau makan apa?
Where to? What do you want to eat? Come on, what do you want to eat?
Eh, cocok-cocok so-spoken gini, buset, guys. Ah! Ayo, ayo.
Hey, matching so-spoken like this, damn, guys. Ah! Come on, come on.
Ya udah nanti di belakang ya. Ya udah.
Okay, later in the back. Okay.
Ya udah, aku lanjut ya. Istirahat dulu ya.
Alright, I'll continue. Rest first.
Ya udah. Kamu jangan capek-capek juga ya. Oke?
Alright. You shouldn't get too tired either, okay?
Iya, iya.
Yeah, yeah.
Makasih. Dah.
Thanks. Bye.
Dadah.
Bye-bye.
Dadah. Ayac-jirus juga, dadah. Ya diantarin sana.
Bye-bye. Ayac-jirus too, bye-bye. Go escort them there.
Owary-mashita kana?
Has it ended yet?
Net-tai... yasumi-tai!
Tropical... I want to rest!
De-ki-mana surprise-nya? Kalian suka enggak? Hah? Kalian suka surprise-nya enggak?
How was the surprise? Did you guys like it? Huh? Did you guys like the surprise?
Eh, Chirusu! Chirusu ini dia yang akan kita obrolin nanti, guys. Hah, kawaii! Kamu nanti bakal dijual banyak ya, Chirusu ya.
Eh, Chirusu! Chirusu, this is the one we'll talk about later, guys. Ha, cute! You're gonna be sold a lot later, Chirusu.
You'll be... you'll be sold by many, many customers. So, please be a good Chirusu. Yeah, yeah.
Kalau gitu kita beneran closing-nya. Semoga kalian senang sama performance tadi. Hai, ja, itu...
If so, we're really doing the closing. Hope you guys enjoyed the performance earlier. Hi, well, that...
Kobo-Kobo...
Kobo-kanaeru Kobo-kanaeru 3rd anniversary, let me be your sun to shine your day!
Kobo Kanaeru 3rd anniversary, let me be your sun to shine your day!
Bui bui sonnanyorokoshingu wai wai!
Boo-boo, everyone's rejoicing, yay, yay!
Tsukareta! Mou owari da!
I'm tired! It's already over!
I'm—I'm fre—friends. I'm friend with the curse.
I'm—I'm fri—friends. I'm friend with the curse.
I'm sorry, I don't know English, but I read that.
No, that's okay. Like, you know...
And you looked too! You looked so shocked on the chat was like, is something wrong?
And you looked too! You looked so shocked on the chat like, is something wrong?
Yeah, yeah. This what I wanna remake the short, the short.
Say dada!
Tadi ada karage...
Earlier there was karaage...
Enggak tahu kamu mengambil yang mana. Karage terus Omuraisu ya.
I don't know which one you took. Karaage then Omurice, yeah.
Morisudaki sae sakira remasuka?
Can Morisudaki even be avoided?
What did you say? What did you say?
I just—I just fumbled sukakakakakaga!
Ya udah. Nah, udah. Ya udah. Gih, sana, tidur. Bye. Da!
Alright. Well, already. Alright. Go there, sleep. Bye. Da!